<idea-plugin url="https://github.com/coderazzi/aws_codeartifact_maven">
  <id>net.coderazzi.aws_codeartifact_maven</id>
  <name>AWS CodeArtifact + Maven</name>
  <version>3.3.1</version>
  <vendor email="lu@coderazzi.net" url="https://coderazzi.net">coderazzi</vendor>

  <description><![CDATA[
    <h1>Support to update AWS CodeArtifact credentials on maven projects.</h1>

    <p>This plugin facilitates accessing and deploying artifacts in CodeArtifact on Maven Intellij Idea projects.</p>

    <p>AWS provides very specific <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codeartifact/latest/ug/maven-mvn.html">instructions</a>
     to set up Maven to support AWS CodeArtifact. Basically, your file ~/.m2/settings.xml must include a server
     specification such as:</p>
<pre>
&lt;settings&gt;
  &lt;servers&gt;
    &lt;server&gt;
      &lt;id&gt;coderazzi-project-yz&lt;/id&gt;
      &lt;username&gt;aws&lt;/username&gt;
      &lt;password&gt;${env.CODEARTIFACT_AUTH_TOKEN}&lt;/password&gt;
    &lt;/server&gt;
 &lt;/servers&gt;
&lt;/settings&gt;
</pre>

    <p>The token CODEARTIFACT_AUTH_TOKEN needs to be refreshed every 12 hours (by default) by doing:</p>
    <pre>export CODEARTIFACT_AUTH_TOKEN=`aws codeartifact get-authorization-token --domain DOMAIN --domain-owner DOMAIN_OWNER --query authorizationToken --output text`</pre>

    <p>After issuing the previous command, the environment that executes the command has authorized access to CodeCommit</p>

    <p>The main problem here is that when using an IDE like IDEA, you would need to update the CODEARTIFACT_AUTH_TOKEN
     environment variable and then launch the IDE. And as the token needs to be refreshed, it is needed to quit the
     IDE and repeat the process every 12 hours. Plus, it is needed to update the environment variable in the same
     environment where the IDE is launched, quite inconvenient if launching the IDE from anywhere except the command line.
    </p>

    <p>Idea allows to set up environment variables for MVN execution
     (under Settings/Build/Execution/Deployment/Build Tools/Maven/Runner),
     but this would imply to manually obtaining the token and updating the setting periodically.</p>

    <p>A better option for this specific scenario is to automatically update the password in ~/.m2/settings.xml,
     to reflect the real token. That is, the settings file will look like:</p>
<pre>
&lt;settings&gt;
  &lt;servers&gt;
    &lt;server&gt;
      &lt;id&gt;coderazzi-project-yz&lt;/id&gt;
      &lt;username&gt;aws&lt;/username&gt;
      &lt;password&gt;REAL_CREDENTIALS_OBTAINED_FROM_AWS&lt;/password&gt;
    &lt;/server&gt;
 &lt;/servers&gt;
&lt;/settings&gt;
</pre>

    <p><b>CodeArtifact-Maven Idea plugin</b> does exactly this simple task. Note that there is an AWS-supported
    AWS plugin, but it does not cover getting credentials for CodeArtifact</p>

   <h2>Installation</h2>

       <p>Plugin available in Intellij Idea public plugin repository, as CodeArtifact+Maven</p>

   <h2>Usage</h2>

    <p>After installation, a menu entry appear under Tools: <b>Generate AWS CodeArtifact credentials for Maven</b></p>

    <p>When selected, a window appears to enter the required details:</p>
    <ul>
     <li><b>Domain</b>: the domain in AWS</li>
     <li><b>Domain Owner</b>: the account owner, something like 023174738914</li>
     <li><b>Maven server id</b>: the server name provided in your maven settings file -as following the instructions from AWS-.
        This is a value obtained already from the maven settings file, using all servers whose username is <b>aws</b></li>
     <li><b>AWS profile</b>: the profile to use to obtain the credentials, obtained from any of the files
      &lt;USER-HOME&gt;/.aws/config, &lt;USER-HOME&gt;/.aws/credentials, &lt;AWS_CONFIG_FILE&gt;,
      &lt;AWS_SHARED_CREDENTIALS_FILE&gt;</li>
     <li><b>Region</b>: the target region. If specified, it overrides the region given by the profile -if any-</li>
     <li><b>Maven settings file</b>: the location of the maven settings file, usually under USER-HOME/.m2</li>
     <li><b>AWS cli path</b>: where to find the <b>aws</b> executable</li>
    </ul>

    <p>The button Generate credentials will initiate the requests of a token to AWS and its inclusion in the maven settings file</p>


    <h2>MFA support</h2>

    <p>From version 3.0.0, the plugin includes support for MFA, prompting the user to enter the MFA token if required.<p>
    <p>Currently, only MFA based on roles is supported, where the chosen profile identifies a IAM role, not a IAM user.<br>
       For more information on the distinction between role-based-MFA and user-based-MFA, check
      <a href="https://coderazzi.net/cloud/aws/mfa">https://coderazzi.net/cloud/aws/mfa</a></p>

    ]]></description>

  <change-notes><![CDATA[
    <ul>
      <li>Version 3.3.1 : 14th Nov 2024: Make plugin compatible with latest IDE version (2024.3).
                          It solves an exception requesting that Access is allowed from write thread only</li>
      <li>Version 3.3.0 : 03rd May 2024: Make plugin compatible with latest IDE version (2024.1)</li>
      <li>Version 3.2.4 : 08th Dec 2023: Make plugin compatible with latest IDE version (2023.3)</li>
      <li>Version 3.2.3 : 19th Sep 2023: Bug using default region for profiles without configured region</li>
      <li>Version 3.2.2 : 29th Jul 2023: SVG correction by Sergio (sfgvieira)</li>
      <li>Version 3.2.1 : 28th Jul 2023: Final solution to avoid exception due to change on internal SVGLoader</li>
      <li>Version 3.2.0 : 27th Jul 2023: Quick patch to avoid exception due to change on internal SVGLoader</li>
      <li>Version 3.1.0 : 21st Apr 2023: User can optionally specify the target region</li>
      <li>Version 3.0.0 : 04th Dec 2022: Added support for MFA (role based)</li>
      <li>Version 2.2.0 : 06th Nov 2022: Added hint in case of missing region configuration (issue #8 in GitHub).</li>
      <li>Version 2.1.1 : 29th Jan 2022: if profile is default, do not include it when getting credentials.</li>
      <li>Version 2.1.0 : 27th Jan 2022: Added AWS profile management.</li>
      <li>Version 2.0.1 : 27th Nov 2021: Removed use of deprecated API, improved dialog layout.</li>
      <li>Version 2.0.0 : 24th Nov 2021: Changed GUI to use dropdowns with serverIds extracted from maven settings file.</li>
      <li>Version 1.1.1 : 23rd Sep 2021: solved bug: "Do not request resource from classloader using path with leading slash".</li>
      <li>Version 1.1.0 : 19th Sep 2021: proper implementation of Cancel button.</li>
      <li>Version 1.0.5 : 13th May 2021: corrected html tags on plugin description and readme.md files</li>
      <li>Version 1.0.4 : 12th May 2021: removed missing image from plugin description.</li>
      <li>Version 1.0.3 : 11th May 2021: compiled with JDK.</li>
      <li>Version 1.0.2 : 10th May 2021: changed name to prefix it with AWS, to facilitate searches.</li>
      <li>Version 1.0.1 : 10th May 2021: added AWS cli path</li>
    </ul>
    ]]>
  </change-notes>

  <idea-version since-build="173"/>

  <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>

  <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
    <applicationService serviceImplementation="net.coderazzi.aws_codeartifact_maven.PluginState"/>
  </extensions>

  <actions>
    <action id="net.coderazzi.aws_codeartifact_maven.LaunchAction" class="net.coderazzi.aws_codeartifact_maven.LaunchAction"
            text="Generate AWS CodeArtifact Credentials for Maven" description="Generate AWS CodeArtifact credentials for Maven"
            icon="AllIcons.Actions.ShowWriteAccess">
      <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" anchor="first"/>

    </action>
  </actions>

</idea-plugin>
